嘿 老头 看着我
Hey, you old man. You look at me.
我有话要跟你说
I got something to say to you.
每次我们去到新的地方
Every time we land someplace new
你说会不一样 结果却没有
you say it's going to be different, but it ain't.
你坏了事 很多事
You mess up. A lot.
然后留给我 妈妈和多萝西去帮你收拾残局
Then you leave a mess for me and Momma and Dorothy to clean up.
这样是不对的 我就想这么说
And that ain't right. That's all I'm saying.
不管怎样 我做了我该做的事情
Hell, I do what I gotta do.
你总是想做就做 能不做就不做
You do whatever the hell you want.Whatever you can get away with.
你就是个自私的老酒鬼
You're just a selfish, old drunk.
没错 那就是你
Yeah, that's what you is.
这个地方的人将捉拿我们
This place is gonna be after us.
他们会找到你
Hell, they'll be on you
然后揍你一顿
and they're going to beat your ass.
我不愿意看到你被打死
And I'd hate to see you go down.
因为你是我爸爸
You know you're my daddy.
你知道自己是谁 对吗?
You know what you are, ain't you?
我在跟你说话
I'm talking at you.
你这次干的事...
What you done this time...
他们肯定会揍你一顿 该死
they'll beat your ass. Shit.
他们会这么干的
That's what they're gonna do.
你可以等着那一天
You can count on it.
事实上 洪水警报原定于今天早上5:45
As a matter of fact, there was flood advisory in effect
开始生效
at 5:45 this morning.
但就在不久前 大概在4:30
But just a few moments ago, as of 4:30,
国家气象服务中心将警报时间提前了
that has been lifted by the National Weather Service.
但根据多普雷雷达估计
But was looking at some of the Doppler radar estimates,
降雨量接近三英寸
and it looked as if close to three inches of rain
伴随着局部的雷阵雨...
fell with a little thunder storm...
- 他们摘到葡萄了?  - 是
- They got the grape?  - Yep.
他们有葡萄 橘子 酸柠檬
They got grape, orange, lemon-lime,
果汁酒
fruit punch.
这种季风天气还让我们来
Got us back here in this monsoon.
让他们集合 朱尼尔!
Round them up, Junior!
还没到午餐时间呢
Yo, it ain't even lunch time yet.
让他们集合
Round them up.
把工具收起来 各位! 我们离开这里 走吧
Let's pack up the gear, guys! Let's get out of here. Let's go.
雨这么大 在外面什么也做不了
Can't get shit did out here in this rain.
我不明白他为什么让我们这么出去 乔
I don't know why he got us out here like this, Joe.
我们去把他们送走
Let's go get them packs off.
一个个来 不要挤
One at a time. One at a time.
嘿 嘿 一个个来
Hey, hey, hey, one at a time.
你们怎么动作这么慢? 你们全他妈像海龟一样!
Why y'all movin' so slow? You look like y'all goddamn turtles out here!
我们都在淋雨啊
It's gettin' rain on us.
走啦! 你们全都过来 离开这里
Let's go! Y'all come on, get out of here.
快点 我们要走啦!
Come on, let's get out of here!
妈的 乔 你什么时候打算买新货车 乔?
Damn, Joe. When you gonna get you a new truck, Joe?
这辆车有什么问题?
What's wrong with this one?
废话 这辆太破 你不能告诉我们它有什么问题吗?
Shit. it raggedy. You can't tell what wrong with it?
你不知道?
You don't know?
- 是啊 你得换辆车了  - 是啊 老兄
- Yeah, you gotta get another one.  - Yeah, man.
给我根烟
Let me get a cigarette.
必须开始从你工资里扣了
Have to start taking this outta your pay.
好啦
All right then.
要是明天出太阳了再见
See you tomorrow if the sun comes up.
早上来叫我 要叫醒我啊
Holla at me in the mornin', and let me know, now.
把衣服放那里 把工具都放下
Put the jerseys in there. Take your work gear off.
所有工具都留在这里
Leave all your work gear in here.
你们快点 把工具留下 走的时候小心周围
Come on y'all, leave the work gear. Quit pussyfootin' around.
大家可以看到雨水往北移出墨西哥
And you can see the moisture moving northward out of Mexico
进入墨西哥湾
and also out into the Gulf of Mexico.
遇到前面的
Meeting up with this frontal system,
缓慢南移的气流
which has slowly been sagging southward.
我们看云层覆盖下的温度
As we look at temperatures with the cloud cover,
并不像我们所看到的那么热
not as hot as what we've been seeing.
但气温下降和加拿大气流并没有关系
But the cool down isn't related to Canadian air.
这是位于城市东北部上空的部分加拿大气流
Here's some Canadian air over the northeastern part of the country.
露水点非常高 这代表有大量的水分能够
Very high dew points, this represents a whole lot of moisture available
上升到这些高空云层 形成暴雨
to rise into those tall clouds producing the heavy rains.
因此今晚的暴雨和雷阵雨...
So the showers and thunderstorms during tonight...
- 早 朱尼尔  - 早 乔
- Morning, Junior.  - Morning, Joe.
你今天早上要去干活?
You going to work this morning?
废话 乔 要是你答应给我加薪 我就会出现
Shit, Joe. If you gimme that raise you promised me, I'll show up.
矮子怎么样? 他昨晚喝醉了吗?
What about Shorty? He get drunk last night?
- 矮子昨晚差点被抓了  - 什么?
- Shorty almost got arrested last night.  - What?
- 他怎么了?  - 没错 差点被抓了
- He what?  - Hell, yeah. Almost got arrested.
他像个弱智一样打那女人的屁股
Hittin' that woman on her ass like he retarded.
好吧 三十分钟后我会去柯尔曼那边 你们都准备好
All right, I'll be up at Coleman's in 30 minutes. Y'all be ready.
我会去的 乔 拜拜
I'll be there, Joe. Bye-bye.
矮子 昨天晚上过得真不容易啊
Shorty, that was a rough night last night.
今早差点就不能上班了 兄弟
Almost didn't make it to work this morning, boy.
你都想不到自己干了什么
You'd be surprised.
喝醉了以后 想去摸这个女人的屁股
Drinkin' and tryin' to touch this lady on her butt.
我实在忍不住
I couldn't help myself.
嘿 你会没事的
Hey, you gonna be all right.
你最好当心点 黑鬼
You better watch yourself, nigga.
乔来了 各位 乔来了
Here's Joe, y'all. Here's Joe.
- 你们把东西放车上  - 快点 帮帮你兄弟
- Let's load up, y'all.  - Come on, y'all help a brother out.
- 早上好 乔  - 早上好
- Good morning, Joe.  - Good morning.
矮子和米尔顿 你们俩跟我来
Shorty and Milton, y'all come with me.
我也不知道为什么
I don't know why either.
这根本说不通 你知道吗?
That don't make no sense though, you know?
你们今天动作真慢
You slow-pokin' today.
- 早 约翰  - 你好 乔
- Morning, John.  - Hello, Joe.
- 来点咖啡吗?  - 我自己来
- You want some coffee?  - I can get it.
- 不是冷的 对吗?  - 对
- It ain't cold, is it?  - No.
昨天是冷的
It was cold yesterday.
让我猜猜 你是米尔顿 对吗?
Let's see now. You're Milton, right?
我是矮子 他才是米尔顿
I'm Shorty, he's Milton.
嘿 萨米今天去哪儿了?
Hey, where's Sammy today?
妈的 萨米去钓鱼了 乔 他跟我说你炒了他
Shit, Sammy gone fishin', Joe. Hell, Sammy told me you fired him.
妈的 我已经炒他三次了
Hell, I've fired his ass three times already.
你告诉萨米 要是他还不开始帮我干活 我会永远炒了他
You tell Sammy I'm gonna fire him for good if he don't start helping me out some.
- 你们要咖啡吗?  - 当然要 老兄
- Y'all want some coffee?  - Yeah, sure, man.
- 昨晚看球赛了吗?  - 看了
- See that ball game last night?  - Yeah.
那些人玩得真烂
Those boys played one hell of a game.
- 谁赢了?  - 当然是我们
- Who won though?  - We did, of course.
矮子 你要加这种香肠吗?
Shorty, you want some of these wieners over here?
随便
I'm good.
矮子 要是你有根这么粗的 你肯定会很受欢迎
Shorty, if you had one like this, you'd be a bad boy. God damn.
无所谓啦
Whatever.
你的和这里的这种一样 极其细小
You got one of these right here, itsy-bitsy, shriveled Slim Jim.
你好像今天没什么事做啊
You actin' like you ain't got nothin' to do today.
你们今天都不在我身边看着我...
Y'all don't quit pussyfootin' around me today...
是啊 你今天得给我减少工作 朱尼尔
Yeah, you gonna get some work outta me, Junior.
好的 你负责东边的这块
All right, you're going to take the east side over here.
- 没问题 就在这里?  - 东边那块
- All right, over here?  - Take east side over there.
- 你能行吗?  - 可以
- You all right?  - Yes, sir.
今天你负责西边那块 行吗?
I want you to take the west side over here today, all right?
妈的 你干嘛像个弱智一样看着我?
Damn, why are you looking at me like you're retarded?
把东西带上 跟他们一起去
Get that thing on and go with them.
矮子 你今天没事吧?
Shorty, you all right today?
- 我没事 老兄  - 感觉非常好吗?
- Yeah, I'm good, man.  - Feeling pretty good?
你今天看起来像"魔鬼克星" 没事吧?
You look like a goddamn Ghostbuster today. You all right?
你今天要这样工作吗?
You gonna fight like one today?
- 你要这样工作吗?  - 我会振作的 老大
- You gonna work like one?  - I'll look right, my man.
- 我很好  - 好吧 不许偷懒
- I'm good.  - All right, don't trip on them.
那是当然
Hell, yeah.
你今天最好干活也像个"魔鬼克星" 矮子
You better do some Ghostbuster moves on me today, Shorty.
好 砍光这些树
Yeah, bust them trees.
我发现一条蛇!
I got a snake!
有条蛇在这里!
I got a snake down here!
最好当心点 老兄
Better watch yourself, man.
我不确定 它看起来像条毒蛇 嘴巴非常大
I don't know. Look like a cottonmouth, that mouth pretty big.
妈的
Damn.
看那个
Look at that.
我不知道它有多大
I dunno how big he is.
嘿 朱尼尔
Hey, Junior.
现在知道是多大了
That's a big one now.
你可以被称为蛇神了
You could be known as the snake god.
不管怎样 我抓到一条更大的 乔
I got one bigger anyway, Joe.
乔 你抓住它的弱点了 乔
Joe, you got nuts of a bear, Joe.
这就是昨晚那个女人告诉我的
That's what that woman told me last night.
她还要一条蛇 我今天就看到一条
She gotta need another snake, I seen one today.
是啊 你抓到好多条了
Yeah, you got a bunch of them.
那个胖女人说了什么
What that fat woman said.
有外人来了
We got company.
让我看看那条蛇
Let me see that snake.
长得很好对吗?
Ain't he a nice one?
看到哪些毒牙了吗?
See those fangs?
你要是被毒牙咬了 你会死的
You get bit by those and you're gonna die.
你会生不如死
You're gonna wanna die.
你们别杀它
Y'all don't kill it.
它是我的朋友
He's my friend.
妈的 乔 别把它扔给我!
Damn, Joe. Don't toss it over by me!
嘿 你们都回去干活
Hey, get back to work, y'all.
表演结束啦
The show is over with.
- 我听到你尖叫了  - 我没有尖叫 我只是跑走了
- I heard you screamin'.  - I wasn't screamin', I just move fast.
随你怎么说
Whatever.
你们都在干嘛? 你们都在砍树吗?
What are y'all doing? Y'all cutting these trees?
我们在杀树
We're killing trees.
为了什么?
What for?
清干净地皮
Neidermeyer land.
老板花钱请我们把上面的东西全都除掉
The owner hires us to get rid of what's on it,
这样他们就能进来 把强壮的松树种上去
so they can come in and put strong pines on it.
没人想要这些树 这些树都快死了
Nobody wants these trees, these trees are weak.
它们拿去做什么都不够好
They're not good for anything.
要是我不盯着他们 那些小伙子会坐下来偷懒
These boys will sit down if I don't stay on their asses.
- 嘿 先生?  - 嗯?
- Hey, mister?  - Yeah?
我有个问题想问你
I got a question for you.
是这样的 我和我爸爸刚刚来到镇上
You see, me and my daddy just got into town
我想请问你
and I was wondering if you'd
能不能给我们一份工作 我们在找工作
give us a job. We're looking for work.
你多大了?
How old are you?
十五岁
Fifteen.
用四十五秒给我一个雇你的理由
Well you've got forty-five seconds to tell me why I should hire you.
我以前做过捆干草 在火车上工作过 还捡过番茄
I baled hay before, I worked on a truck, I picked tomatoes,
西葫芦 黄瓜
zucchini, cucumbers,
黄秋葵 南瓜...
okra, squash...
好了 你能吃苦 很好
All right, you're not afraid of work. Good.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
盖瑞·琼斯
Gary Jones.
我叫乔
I'm Joe.
干一天活 领一天的工资
I pay a day's pay for a day's work.
我每周五发工资 所以你今天可以挣一点
I pay on Fridays, so you'll get a little something today,
但你第一个正式领工资的日子是下周五
but your first real payday is next Friday.
我们早上六点左右开工
We start at about 6:00 in the morning,
一点或两点收工
quit at 1:00 or 2:00.
如果我们工作到晚上或者遇到下雨停工 我会支付一整天的工资
If we work till dinner or get rained out, I pay for the whole day.
- 听起来够公平吗?  - 公平 先生
- Does that sound fair enough?  - Yes, sir.
- 沿着这排树走  - 好的 先生
- Follow this line of trees.  - Yes, sir.
大概走半英里就能回到我的车
Close to a half a mile back to my truck.
果汁斧头在后备箱
The juice hatchets are in the back.
你给自己拿一个 涂满毒药
You get yourself one, fill it up with poison,
然后沿着原路返回
then come on back the same way you went out.
- 好的 先生  - 不要迷路了
- Yes, sir.  - And don't get lost.
不会的
I won't.
嘿!
Hey!
你不想知道你的工资是多少吗?
Don't you want to know how much you're getting paid?
你好吗?
How you doing?
- 很好  - 你能行吗?
- Good.  - You doing all right?
- 你今天准备好干活了?  - 是的 先生
- You ready to work today?  - Yes, sir.
- 我叫朱尼尔  - 我是盖瑞
- I'm Junior.  - Gary.
你好 盖瑞 我今天会看着你
Hello, Gary. I'm gonna be over you today.
举起你的右手 你要发誓
Raise your right hand. You're gonna have to swear
你会努力为我工作
that you're gonna work hard for me.
不是那只手 你的右手 另外一只
Not that hand, your right hand, your other right.
你的右手 就是这只
Your right hand, there you go.
把手举起来 你要发个誓
Put your hand up, you gotta swear on somethin'.
现在你进入全明星队了
Now you on the all-star team.
- 你保证努力干活?  - 是的 先生
- You promise to work hard?  - Yes, sir.
很好 虽然我不知道乔为什么会选择你 但你肯定是个不错的人
All right, 'cause I don't know why Joe chose you, you must be a good man.
我们做的第一件事就是把这些容器装满
First thing we do is fill these containers up.
我们就像这样把它放进去
We just gonna put it in there like that.
一旦我们很好地装满了 我们就出发
And once we get filled up real good, then we on.
毒药里有什么?
What's in the poison?
天知道 矮子和他的奶奶在地下室做的
Shit. Shorty and his grandma make it in their basement.
我不知道里面有什么 但我们不必担心这个
I don't know what's in it, but we ain't gonna worry about that.
我知道它很好用就够了
I know it work real good.
你觉得这东西很容易抽 是吗?
You thought that was easy pumpin' that thing, didn't you?
看起来我做得容易 因为我是个男人
I made it look easy 'cause I'm a man.
看看你这个小男孩 你得搞定它 明白我的意思吗?
See, you a little boy, you got to figure it out. See what I'm sayin'?
去吧 看看你怎么搞定它?
There you go. See how you figured that out?
等你长成男人了 还有大把事情要你去搞定
When you become a man, you gonna have everything figured out, too.
小心点 现在 这东西真的是有毒的了
Be careful. Now, this stuff is real poisonous.
要是它进了你的眼睛 小弟 你就得走了
If it gets in your eyes, man, you out of there.
不懂就问朱尼尔
Just ask Junior.
现在开始吧
Now here you go.
你用哪只手?
Which hand you use?
- 右手  - 好
- Right hand.  - Okay.
出手前抬高一点 不停地挥
Prime it up a little bit, and keep slinging it.
要是你砍得够用力 你只要砍三四次就可以了
If you hit it hard enough, you only have to hit it three or four times.
一... 二...
One... Two...
你要对树生气 小弟
You got to get angry at the tree, man.
对它疯狂起来 没错 我喜欢这样的
Get mad at it. Yeah, I like that.
对它疯狂起来 继续砍它
Get mad at it. Keep on workin' it.
砍它 砍它!
Work with it, work with it!
好的 先生! 明白!
Yes, sir! Get it!
继续砍 年轻人
Keep on with it, youngster.
我喜欢这样 小弟
I like that, man.
乔一直在周围 他一直在周围不远 小弟
Joe's been around. He's been around a little bit, man.
他的腰带下有样东西 小弟
He's got some things up under his belt, man.
所以我建议你 你要是真的跟着乔干
So I advise you, when you do go to Joe,
要对乔保持诚实
keep it real with Joe.
任何事情都不要骗他
Don't lie to him about nothin',
还有一个乔真的很特别的地方 小弟
and one thing Joe is real particular about, man,
别看地板 要看着他的脸
don't ever look down at the ground. Look him in the face.
他喜欢看着别人的眼睛
He likes to see a man's eyes.
就跟你 一对一 乔就是这样
You, one-on-one. That's how Joe is, man.
你从哪儿来?
Where you from?
- 没有固定的地方  - 在这附近?
- Everywhere.  - Been around?
你还这么小就没有固定去处?
Being a little bitty boy and you been everywhere?
你爸爸是军人还是什么的吗?
Was your daddy in the military or somethin'?
是吗? 好吧 你家在这边吗?
Yeah? All right. You got a family?
好吧
All right then.
你知道我们不会对你有例外 对吧?
You know we ain't gonna out you no slack out here, don't you?
因为你现在还太小嘛
Just 'cause you young, now.
我们是不会放松的 每个人都要背自己的装备
You know we ain't gonna out no slack. Everybody pulls they own load, baby.
只要我们把这东西装满了
Once we get this filled up here,
我们就能砍一百棵树
we can kill us about 100 trees with this here.
伐木不违法吗?
Is killing trees against the law?
除非树死了 木材公司才能砍
Well, the lumber company can't cut them down unless they dead.
所以木材公司雇我们
And so the lumber company hire us to come in
来荼毒这些树
and poison the trees.
所以我们可以砍树 然后让这些树自己死
So we can kill them and they come in and die themselves.
我已经砍了好一阵子树枝了
Yeah, I been doing this for a little minute now.
- 欢迎加入  - 谢谢
- Welcome to the program.  - Thanks.
这个活儿还比较轻松
It's hard work out here.
你要用弯刀把这些东西都砍掉
Well, the machete crew is the one that comes through and clears it out.
砍到差不多你脚踝的高度
Chop down at your angles.
越低越好
Try to get as low as you can.
你得为你的队友砍出一条路
You got to clear the path for your teammates.
没有你 一切都没戏
Without you, none of this is gonna happen.
要不断的砍 绝对不要停
And just keep hammering at it. Nothing stopping you.
恩 你开始砍吧 等一下你可能得当一会儿送水工
Yeah, you start out, you'll probably be the Waterman for a little while.
你得帮他们每个人跑腿
It's gonna look like you're doing everything for everyone,
给他们送水 最后 你就会成为一个弯刀高手
bringing them water. At the end, you'll become a machete vet.
武士之王 就在这里
Samurai kings, right here.
欢迎加入我们的队伍 你是最小的 在你学走路之前得先学会爬
Welcome to the crew, you the youngest. Gotta crawl before you walk.
你很有活力
You got a lot of energy there.
就这样吧
There you go.
武士之神
Samurai gods.
全体队员! 你们把这边砍完之后
Crew! When y'all get through with this side over here,
我们就去西边
we're going to the west side.
好的
All right.
嘿 盖瑞! 你跑得太远了
Hey, Gary! You're getting too far ahead.
回来帮这边的人
Come on back here and help these fellas out.
知道吗? 你 你 还有你
You know what? You, you, and you.
今天干得很不错
Y'all did a good job today.
赶紧去领钱吧 我们星期一再见 如何?
Why don't y'all go ahead and get paid, and I'll see y'all Monday. All right?
小子
Little.
- 阿兰  - 谢谢 先生
- Alan.  - Thank you, sir.
还有盖瑞 对吗?
And Gary, right?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
盖瑞 盖瑞 盖瑞...
Gary, Gary, Gary...
星期一再过来
Come back Monday.
如果你爸爸也想干活的话 就带他过来
Bring your daddy if he wants to work.
是的 先生 我会来的
Yes, sir. I will.
我们会来的 谢谢
We'll be there. Thanks.
妈妈!
Momma!
嘿 妈妈 你猜怎么着?
Hey, Momma. Guess what?
我今天找到工作了
I got us jobs today.
I got a job today.
你真棒 宝贝
Good for you, babies.
嘿 多萝西!
Hey, Dorothy!
- 多萝西 你猜今天怎么着?  - 他找到工作了
- Dorothy, guess what?  - He got one.
真不错
That's good.
啊
Aw.
抱歉
Sorry.
把那畜生关起来了?
Got that asshole put away?
好了 乔 已经把他关在后面了
Yes, Joe. He's in the back.
要是那畜生再咬我...
That asshole bites me again...
好吧 他本性就那么狂暴
Well, he's got the devil in him.
去他妈的
Fuck that.
进来吧 宝贝
Come on, baby.
你看看
Look at that.
墨西哥游戏节目 我说的就是这个
Mexican game show. That's what I'm talking about.
你要喝点儿什么 宝贝?
Can I fix you somethin', baby?
可乐 加冰
Coke. Ice.
给你 亲爱的
Here you go, sweetie.
怎么看起来闷闷不乐的 乔
So what you got the blues over, Joe?
没那么糟吧
I'm not so bad.
要不要来个姑娘?
Want one of my girls?
还是要两个?
You want two of my girls?
今天不要
Not today.
今天是特别的日子
Today is a special day.
是吗?
It is?
我只想让你陪我 梅尔
I only want your company, Merle.
- 谢谢  - 过来
- Why, thank you.  - Come here.
把那个畜生带走!
Put that asshole away!
蕾西! 把狗关到后院
Lacy! Put the dog in the back.
好了 我知道了
Come on. I got it.
过来
Come on.
你不需要那玩意儿照顾你
You don't need that thing to take care of you.
你要去哪儿 乔?
Where are you going, Joe?
姑娘 给我站起来
Girl, get your ass off the floor.
别犯二了
Quit being stupid.
你看到那是谁了没?
You see who that was?
看到了
Yes.
那是一战还是二战时候的? 你哪儿来的那帽子?
What is that World War I or II? Where'd you get that hat?
- 二战的帽子  - 这样啊
- Ww II.  - Right.
我在参加海陆军的时候拿到的
Got it down there at the Army-Navy.
我在亨利之家玩骰子赢了不少钱
I've been making some money over at Henry's house, throwing the dice.
是啊 我知道 我本来还打算去那儿把他赢个干净的
Yeah, I know. I was gonna go over there later and clean him out.
我可能在那儿见到你
Maybe I'll see you there.
我非常擅长从那些老太太那里赢钱
I've been doing pretty good taking the money from them old ladies
那些老太太经常和和还有老瞎子乔治一起出去
that he and old Blind George hang outwith.
我有百分之六七十的胜率
I take about 60 or 70% of my winnings
然后我把钱全捐给糖尿病研究
and donate it to diabetes research.
但是后来我就把剩下的钱
But then I take the rest of it
都用来买战争用品了
and buy war paraphernalia.
总有一天我会成为一个正规的美国军
One of these days, I'm gonna be a regular GI Joe.
荒野大镖客!
Fistful of dollars!
差不多就这种
Something like that.
亨利!
Henry!
里面 乔!
In here, Joe!
你跟我说你知道怎么弄的
You told me you knew how to do this.
嘿 乔
Hey, Joe.
你怎么样啊? 今天忙什么了?
How you been doin'? What are you up to today?
- 谁来了?  - 亨利已经弄得一团糟了
- Who's that?  - Henry's just making a damn mess.
- 你在干嘛呢 亨利?  - 我不知道
- What are you tryin' to do, Henry?  - I don't know.
- 他弄得太糟了  - 我没有割鹿肉的经验
- He's making a damn mess.  - I don't have experience
知道吗?
to cut this deer, you know?
这鹿真大 但是要知道 想要剔骨烤肉的话...
It's big one, you know, but tryin' to out it in roasts, you know, but...
是啊 不过我觉得我是不会切了拿去烤的
Yeah, well, I don't think I would cut it into a roast.
不会
No.
你想怎么样都行 不过要是我的话 我会切成肉排
You can do anyway you want to, but if it was mine, I'd cut it into steaks.
过来给他看看应该怎么弄 宝贝
Come over here and show him how to do it, honey.
亨利 你赶紧坐那儿 给我讲讲笑话唱唱歌什么的吧
Henry, you can sit down there and tell me a joke or sing a song or something.
好吧 该死 你应该也让瞎子乔治来切一切
Well, shit. You might as well just let Blind George cut it up.
我要去坐着了
I'm gonna sit down.
我是说 乔治也可以切
I mean, George could cut it up.
只要你给他足够的时间 不是吗 乔治?
If you gave him enough time, couldn't you, George?
我觉得我能比他们切的都好
I reckon I can do better than they are doing it.
不可能
No.
好吧 我给你们示范一下怎么切肉排
All right. I'll show you how to make the steaks.
那真是太好了 宝贝儿 我爱死里脊了
That'll be good, baby. I love backstrap.
扶住点儿 没错 就是这样
Hold on here. That's good, that's enough.
现在看看这只可怜的鹿会有什么下场
Now look what happened to the poor thing.
流了一地的血 天啊
All that blood on the floor, God.
你哪儿弄来的这头鹿?
Where'd you get this deer?
它就在李先生的围栏那边晃来晃去
It was hung up on the fence, over at Mr. Lee's.
亨利和我正好从烤博饼店出来
And Henry and I was coming back from the IHOP
然后我带着我的点三八手枪 然后一枪给它爆头
and I took out my .38 and shot her in the head.
宝贝 你用刀的感觉就像是艺术家用画笔
Honey, you use that knife just like an artist's brush.
我是说你这手艺真不错 乔
I mean, you know what you're doing, Joe.
伙计 来看看这个
Man, look at that.
天啊...
Man...
这块肉相当不错
There's some good stuff here.
- 的确很不错  - 现在 你看
- That is some good stuff.  - Now, look here.
伙计 真的太棒了
Man, that is pretty.
没错 棒极了
Yes, wonderful.
你要这么切 蝴蝶型的肉排
That's how you do it. Butterfly steak.
- 太棒了  - 看到我怎么切的了吗?
- Wonderful.  - You see how I did that?
那就在这里 这里 还有这里切开
Now do it here, here, and here.
你们都来吧剩下的切掉吧
Y'all can cut up the rest of it.
那么你们另外一个无聊游戏什么时候开始?
So, when are you gonna have another crap game?
今晚 你要来吗?
Tonight. You wanna come by?
- 几点?  - 十点
- What time?  - 10:00.
我们要做一个生日蛋糕
We're making a birthday cake.
我们? 乔 你知道是谁来做生日蛋糕吗?
We? Joe, you know who's gonna make the birthday cake.
我今晚得做生日蛋糕
I'm gonna make a birthday cake tonight.
对吗 史黛西?
Right, Stacy?
我爱你 亨利 但是你知道吗?
I love you, Henry, but you know what?
我特么才是过生日的那个
I am the fucking birthday girl here,
然后我还得给自己做一个该死的蛋糕?
and I have to make my own damn cake?
那可不是我的问题
That's not my problem.
没错 我会给自己做个生日蛋糕的 没问题
Sure, I'll make me a birthday cake, no problem.
我要去镇上 你们需要什么吗?
I gotta go uptown. Y'all need anything?
我要点儿冷冻纸
I think I need some freezer paper.
给我带点儿冷冻纸回来吧
Bring me back some damn freezer paper,
再带一包烟
and another pack of cigarettes.
- 好东西  - 我们爱你 宝贝
- Good stuff.  - We love you, baby.
里脊肉 是最基本的部分 我只吃...
That backstrap, well, that's the part that basically, I only eat...
你好 乔
Hello, Joe.
等会儿 伙计
Hold on, buddy.
乔 你还好吗?
Joe, you all right?
出什么事儿了?
What happened?
女士们 先生们 女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen. Ladies and gentlemen.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
现在能走了吗?
Can we go now?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
你打算去哪儿?
Where you gonna go?
我们要去镇上买点吃的 快来
We gonna go into town and get some food. Come on.
要买什么东西吃? 我们这边几乎什么都买不到
Get something to eat with what? We ain't got hardly nothing here.
好吧 东西是没那么多 但是也总是有一些吧 快走吧
Well, it ain't much, but it's something. Come on.
我起不来了
I ain't getting up.
- 你喝醉了?  - 我没醉
- Are you drunk?  - I ain't drunk.
- 我知道你醉了  - 不 我没醉
- I know you drunk.  - No, I ain't drunk.
你这样 "我没喝醉..."
You like, "I ain't drunk..."
我今天没吃药 孩子
I didn't take my medicine today, boy.
- 我还没吃药  - "我只是很累"
- I didn't take my medicine.  - "I'm just tired."
"我没喝醉"
"I ain't drunk."
快来吧 起来
Come on, get up.
起来吧
Come on.
快 起来
Come on, get up.
拜托了 起来吧
Come on, please.
你没问题的 快 我扶你起来
You'll be all right, come on. I'll help you up.
你能行的
You can make it.
啊 不行 我跟你说...
Yeah, no, you know what...
我就打算坐在这儿 坐在尘土里
I'm gonna sit right here, in the dirt.
我教你一点儿霹雳舞吧
I'm gonna teach you a little about breakdancing.
你以前看过霹雳舞吗?
You ever seen breakdancing before?
你知道机械舞和锁舞吗?
You know what popping, you know what locking is?
你知道吗 小家伙?
Do you, bud?
把这只手放在这儿
Take this hand right here,
想象你在海上随波飘荡
pretend it's going over a wave like you're out there in the ocean.
你漂浮着 快来 儿子 你随波飘荡着
You floating. Come on, son. You floating out there in the ocean.
潮汐从这边到这边
Tidal wave coming across the bottom to the other side.
我们走
Here we go. Yeah.
我们正在摇晃
We're waving now.
再回来 有一个大浪过来了!
Bring it back up. Here comes the big one!
耶! 就是这样
Yeah! There it is.
嘿! 嘿!
Hey! Hey!
现在 现在这样可不好玩
Now, now, that shit ain't funny, right there.
这样可一点都不好玩
That shit ain't funny at all.
我要把我的酒拿回来
I'll come get it now.
- 你想要? 想要酒吗?  - 想要
- You want it? You want it?  - Yeah.
我没有上完我的课 人生的课
I'm not through with my lesson, life's lesson.
你只学会来回晃
You only learned about waving.
机械舞 你见过机械舞吗?
Popping, you ever seen popping?
砰! 那就是机械舞
Pop! That's popping.
你知道锁舞吗?
You know what locking is?
我做不来一整套的锁舞 除非我...
I really can't do a whole lot of locking unless I'm...
除非我站起来 然后...
Unless I'm standing, and...
- 那么就站起来 快点  - 我看不到在不远的将来
- Well, stand up, come on.  - I don't see myself doing much of that
我有做什么有意义的事儿 儿子
in the near future there, son.
我知道你醉了 你都快把酒撒了
I know you're drunk because you're about to spill it.
我为什么要把酒撒了呢? 我只是需要个枕头
Why would I spill it? I need a pillow.
真不错
There we go. Yeah.
一 二...
One, two...
嘿 先生!
Hey, mister!
Hey, mister.
能不能载我们一程?
Can you give me a ride?
再说一次?
Say it again?
我和我爸爸想知道你能不能顺路载我们去镇上
Me and my daddy was wondering if you could give us a ride back into town.
他身体不太舒服
He ain't feeling too good.
当然可以
Shit, yeah.
没问题 我会载你们一程
Yeah, I'll give you boys a ride.
过来 你老爸在哪儿?
Come on, where's your daddy at?
他在后面一点
He's back that a way.
你为什么要把枪扔下去?
What did you chunk that gun off the bridge for?
我只是扔了它
I just threw it.
你知道吗?
You know?
武器会让人们做出暴力的事情
Weapons tend to make men do violent things.
是的
Yeah.
枪
Guns,
刀
knives,
炮弹 炸弹雷管
cannonballs, little sticks of dynamite.
该死 甚至连汽车都会
Hell, even automobiles.
嘿 过来
Hey, come here.
看着我的脸
Look at my face.
看到没?
You see that?
我看到了
I see it.
有一天早上凌晨四点我穿过了挡风玻璃
I went through a windshield at 4:00 one morning,
我他妈的无所谓
and I don't give a fuck.
听着
Now,
那些家伙找来的麻烦比他们想象得要多
folks looking for trouble tend to find more than they're after.
如果他胆敢再扇我巴掌 我一定杀了他
And I'll kill his fucking ass if he ever slaps me again,
你听明白了吗?
you understand me?
你在说谁?
Who you talking about?
如果他胆敢
If he ever
再扇
slaps
我的话
me again.
你有姐妹吗?
You got any sisters?
什么?
What?
姐妹
Sisters.
你有姐妹吗?
You got any sisters?
她漂亮吗?
Is she pretty?
先生 请你不要提我的妹妹
Mister, don't you talk about my sister.
他妈的
Well, shit.
你还真是个难搞的贱货 对吧?
You're a tough little son of a bitch, ain't you?
你在跟谁说话呢?
Who the fuck you talking to?
我在跟你说话 先生 请你尊重我的家人
I'm talking to you, mister. Don't you disrespect my family.
你知道我在想什么吗?
You know what I think?
我在想他妈想说什么就说什么
I think I'm gonna say whatever the fuck I wanna say.
给我让开 先生 我从未对你做过什么
You get the hell off me, mister. I ain't done nothing to you.
我不想再顺带你一程了
I don't think I'm gonna give you that ride no more.
我要把你抓住 然后扔到桥下面
I think I'm gonna take you, and I'm gonna throw you off that bridge.
看你喜不喜欢
See how you like that.
看着我 孩子
Look at me, son.
看着我的脸
Look at my face.
有一天早上凌晨四点我穿过了挡风玻璃
I went through a windshield at 4:00 one morning,
我他妈的无所谓
and I don't give a fuck.
看着我 你这个狗崽子!
Look at me, you son of a bitch!
你这个婊子养的! 你以为我是小孩吗?
You stupid motherfucker! You think I'm a kid?
你觉得我他妈的就是个小孩吗?
You think I'm a goddamn kid?
我要痛打你一顿 你才能知道谁他妈的还是个孩子
I'll beat your ass, and now you know it's true.
安静点!
Quiet!
乔?
Joe?
乔
Joe.
- 它会咬我吗?  - 他妈的 给我闭嘴!
- Is he gonna bite me?  - God damn it, would you shut up!
别叫了 回你的窝去 不要打扰这几位女士!
Shut up and get back up under there,and let these ladies alone!
回去!
Get!
你们都进来吧
Y'all come on.
我的狗不会咬人的
Dog won't bite.
那狗真疯狂 如果你不在家我们会怎么样?
God, that dog's crazy. What if you hadn't been here?
如果我不在 你们也不可能到我家的院子来
If I hadn't been here, you wouldn't have no business in my goddamn yard.
天啊 你出了什么事?
Damn, what's happened to you?
稍等
Hang on a minute.
他妈的
Fuck.
你家好乱啊 乔
Place is a mess, Joe.
我没想到有人会来
I wasn't expecting company.
呃 我们就是开车四处逛逛 找点事做
Well, we was just driving around, looking for something to do.
我们也不知道你会不会在家
Didn't know if you'd be home or not.
嗨...
Hey...
你怎么样?
Are you all right?
以后不能再抽烟了
I gotta quit smoking.
到底出什么事了?
What the hell happened to you?
几天前晚上 我在酒吧里扇了一个混蛋一巴掌
I slapped some asshole the other night at the bar.
他找到了我 朝我开了一枪
He come back and shot me.
天啊 乔
Jesus, Joe.
所以你和威利·罗素又跟小孩一样
What, you and Willie-Russell be running around
四处鬼混了?
acting like kids again?
太荒谬了 我都记不得你是因为什么才出来混的
It's ridiculous. I don't even remember what set you off in the first place.
我也记不得了
Neither do I.
你想跟我说什么来着?
So what was it you wanted to talk about?
需要钱吗?
You need some money?
不是的
No, nothing like that.
你知道那个叫弗兰克的家伙吗? 那家伙吗?
You know that guy, Frank? The guy?
他回来了 我也不想住在我妈那
He's back in town, and I don't wanna stay at my momma's.
我记得你妈把他赶走了
Well, I thought she ran him off.
确实 赶走了两次
She did. Twice.
但是有天晚上他给我家打电话了 他说...
But he called the other night, and...
他回来是想求得原谅的
Came back begging for forgiveness.
我妈说只要他不来烦我 他想待多久就可以待多久
She said he could stay as long as he promised to leave me alone.
他也答应了
And he promised.
他之前的几次也是这么答应的
Just like he always does.
但是...
But...
你还有工作吗? 还在洗衣店干吗?
Still got your job? Up at the cleaners?
好
Good.
我不会在这待很久的
I wouldn't even hardly be here.
我能照顾照顾你
I could take care of you.
如果你同意的话
If you let me.
我发誓 我不会跟我妈说我住在哪里
I promise, I won't even tell her where I'm at.
你不用告诉她 她也会知道的
You won't have to. She'll know.
她已经打了四十次电话来找你
She already called here 40 times looking for you.
如果你需要的话 你可以住过来
You can stay with me if you need to.
虽然我不能保证
I can't promise you much,
但是我会尽量对你友善一点
but I'll try to be nice.
一 二 三 六 十一
One, two, three, six, eleven.
好好干 你们除了衣服上的标号 什么也不是!
Get off yo ass, you ain't nothing but a number!
开始干活了 大家伙
Let's go, y'all.
萨米 你去哪里了? 我最近都没有看到你
So, Sammy. Where you been? I haven't seen you around.
你是去了夜校还是什么学校吗?
You going to those night school classes or something?
还没有
Not yet.
我也在干点别的活
Been doing a little work on the side,
想挣点外快 生活得好一点
trying to make a little extra cash. Get my shit together.
- 你知道我的意思吗?  - 我明白你的意思
- You know what I mean?  - I know what you mean.
我们之间的合作对你来说已经不够好了 是吗 萨米?
I know. We're just not good enough for you anymore, are we Sammy?
我可没这么说
I didn't say that.
那些帮你干活的白人都是谁?
Who these white folks you got working?
他们啊 我也不了解
Yeah, I'm not sure.
他们需要找活干 我也需要帮忙
They need work and I need help.
年轻的 年老的 黑的 白的 红的 黄的...
Young, old, black, white, red, yellow...
我真的不关心 萨米
I really don't give a shit, Sammy.
水!
Water!
我他妈的要喝点水
Drink of fucking water.
那是我的水 你为什么喝我的水?
That's my water there. Why you drinking my water?
渴了呗 还能为什么
Thirsty, that's why.
- 又渴又热  - 但你弄脏我的水了
- Thirsty and hot.  - Yeah, but that got them water flavor.
这是我自己的水 你为什么喝我的水?
That's my personal water. Why you drinking my water up like that?
你是不是整天都要给我们添麻烦?
We gonna have a problem outta you all day?
如果我再发现你喝我的水的话 我就要给你找麻烦了
If I catch you with my water again, you gonna have a problem outta me.
乔派你过来跟我一起干的?
Joe sent you down here with me?
- 没错  - 我来帮你背包
- Yeah.  - Let me help you with that pack.
这玩意是怎么用的?
What the hell you use this thing for?
我教你怎么做
I'll show you how to walk through it.
他妈的 真重
God damn. Thing's heavy.
你用这边的这个控制杆挤压出药水
You use this lever right here to pump out the poison.
拿着这把斧头 砍进树里
Take this hatchet and hit into the tree.
你自己试一试
Let's see what you got.
对 就在那
Okay, right here.
- 这他妈的流得到处都是  - 它确实会这样
- Goddamn thing is leaking all over.  - It happens sometimes.
赶紧开始干活 看看你怎么样 就砍这儿
Let's get to work. Let see it, right here.
太扯了
This is bullshit, right here.
快点 伙计 挥你的斧头
Come on, man. Swing it.
挥得用力点
You gotta swing harder than that.
快点啊 伙计 砍进去
Come on, man. Get into it.
伙计 这些都太操蛋了
Man, this is some stupid-ass shit, man.
这是为什么他现在不能吃巧克力了
That's how he can't eat chocolate now.
你们这些黑鬼...
Y'all niggas is...
你们这些黑鬼一靠近我 我一点都不饿了
Y'all niggas is near, I ain't hungry no more.
我不会告诉你们我梦到了什么的 但是...
Ain't gonna tell you what I was dreaming about, what I had, though...
我不想知道 朱尼尔
I don't wanna know, Junior.
我不想知道你的眼镜蛇怎么样了 你叫那玩意什么来着
I don't wanna know about your king cobra, okay. Or whatever you call it.
"上吧 小舌头" 这就是他取的名字
Go-Go-Gadget Tongue, that's what he got.
你从来没注意过你女朋友的那个地方吗 伙计?
You ain't never notice that about your girl, man?
她的胸部一个大一个小
One of her breasts is bigger than the other one, man.
- 等等  - 应该是一个翘
- Wait a minute.  - One sits up here,
另一个趴
and the other one sits down there.
我不回答 不回答
No comment. No comment, nigga.
你这个混蛋...
You nasty...
- 不要先从头开始  - 我没有先从...
- Don't go head first.  - I don't go...
矮子不愿意告诉我们为什么他要去挂水
Shorty don't want to tell us the truth about them drips he had, man,
为什么要注射盘尼西林
about that penicillin shot, man.
说谎 说谎 肯定是在说谎
That's a lie. That's a damn lie. That's a damn lie.
今天天气不错啊 是吧?
Sure is a beautiful day out here, ain't it?
还行
It's all right.
你坐在这就像个天使一样 坐在这么漂亮的阳光下
You sitting out here like an angel, sitting out here under this pretty sun.
也许我就是个天使
Maybe I am an angel.
是啊 但是你必须帮忙完成我的工作 你现在一点帮助都没有
Yeah, but you got to go to work on my job. You ain't on my job working.
为什么你今天不干活?
Why you not working today?
怎么 你过来就是要给我难堪的?
What, you just come up here to give me a hard time?
我看着你不停地喝酒
Well, I been looking at you all goddamn clay,
还来这抽烟
and I see you up here smoking a goddamn cigarette,
他妈的欣赏风景... 你是在找抽吧
watching this, goddamn... Well, I think you a pretty son of a bitch out here.
我们来这是干活的
And we got to come out here to work.
我不知道为什么你不认真干活
I don't know why you ain't trying to work.
我今天该干的活已经干完了
I done all the work I'm gonna do today.
放屁 你什么都没干 你这个酒鬼
Hell, you ain't did shit, all goddamn clay.
你一件屁事都没干
You ain't done a motherfucking thing.
你是谁啊 你来告诉我我今天一天什么都没干?
And who are you to tell me I ain't done nothing at all today?
只要你在这干活 我就是你的老板
As long as you out here, I'm your boss.
你才不是我的老板 很显然你都不看看你的手下干了些什么
You ain't my boss, and obviously you can't even watch what people are doing.
因为如果你看了 你就知道我一天都在干活
'Cause if you saw anything, you'd know I've been working all day.
我他妈的整天都在干活 一整天
I've been working all damn day. All day.
不是 你整天都在乱晃
No, you been dragging your ass all goddamn day.
你想要跟我吵架?
Who's trying to argue with who?
你什么也没干... 我在劝你好好干活
You ain't did shit all goddamn... I'm trying to get you to working.
- 伙计 你有六个手下都坐在那边啊!  - 你他妈的什么都没干!
- Man, you got about six other people! out there.  - You ain't did shit all goddamn day!
我说了 给我干活去!
I told you to goddamn get to working!
要么你就他妈的赶紧给我走!
You gotta get your ass outta my motherfucking job!
那你现在就跟乔说! 去跟他说啊!
Go tell Joe right now! Go tell him!
乔很快就不得不把你赶走 或者对你做点什么
Joe goddamn gonna have to get rid of you or do something different.
今天有事要发生
Something gonna change today.
因为明天我再也不要见到这个混蛋
'Cause tomorrow we ain't gonna have this bullshit.
- 你说完了吗?  - 没错 我他妈的说完了...
- Are you done?  - Yeah, I'm done with this bullshit...
很好 很高兴你终于说完了!
Good, I'm glad you're done!
很高兴你说完了 别再说了
I'm glad you're done. Stay done.
看看你的脸跟酵母菌感染样的!
Look like you got a yeast infection on your goddamn face!
你这个乡下来的狗崽子
You country motherfucker.
- 你能出来吗?  - 也许能吧 我试试
- Can you make it out of there?  - Yeah. I'll make it, I guess.
屁股疼
Goddamn ass hurts.
过来 儿子
Come here, son.
帮我跨下后挡板
Help me get over this tailgate.
乔 早上我们什么时候过来?
Joe, what time you need us back in the morning?
我不需要你们早上过来了
I don't need you back in the morning.
什么叫不需要我们了?
What do you mean, you don't need us back?
我们把活都干了 不是吗?
We got the job done, didn't we?
孩子 这是你的报酬
That's yours there, son.
我们把活都干了 盖瑞说我们有工作了
We got the job done. Gary said we got the job.
乔 你说什么我都会答应你
Joe, I'll do anything you want.
任何时间地点 你想要让我清理灌木丛
Clear brush, anytime, anywhere.
我都可以的
I can do it.
乔 我想要再多干些活
Joe, I'd sure like to work some more.
好的 以后再说吧
Yeah, maybe later.
我会通知你的
I'll let you know.
我不知道你做了什么让那个人生气了
I don't know what you did that made that man mad, or something.
你听见了没?
You hear me?
你他妈的在看什么?
What the hell are you looking at?
再忍一天吧
Just another day.
这不是他的错
It ain't his fault.
他是爱我们的 只是...
He loves us, it's just...
他正在经历痛苦
He just goes through hard times.
但我是不会坐在一边看着他像打我一样地打你 你听见了吗?
Well, I ain't gonna watch him sit there and hit you like he hits me. You hear me?
妈妈?
Okay, Momma?
任何人都不能随随便便地打人
You ain't supposed to do that to no one.
你应该跟家人待在一起
You stay with your family.
这是你该做的
That's what you need to do.
你应该跟家人待在一起
You need to stay with your family.
你的家人是你的所有
Your family's all you got.
这是什么?
What was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我没听到有车开过来的声音
Didn't hear no car drive up.
可能不是什么人 没人会出现在这儿
Probably ain't nobody. Ain't nobody with any sense out in this.
喝不出来
Can't taste that.
我们今晚出去吗?
We gonna go out tonight?
不太想
Not really.
你想去哪?
Where you wanna go?
不知道
I don't know.
我只是想问问我们有没有安排
I was just wondering if we were gonna do something.
你工作得太累了
I think you work too much.
我们应该出去
We should get out.
好好玩玩
Do something fun.
我没有这个打算...
I hadn't planned on it...
除非你真的想去
Not unless you want to.
我们也不一定非要出去
We don't have to.
有人在外面
There's someone out there.
不 不 等等
No. No, wait.
拿着
Hold this.
嗨 乔 你能把那狗牵走吗?
Hey, Joe. Can you put that dog up?
该死 我知道是谁了
Hell. I know who it is.
孩子 你全身都湿了
Boy, you're soaking-ass wet.
你打算怎么办 整夜都站在那?
What'd you plan to do, stand there all night?
他应该把湿衣服脱掉 不然会生病的
He should get out of them wet clothes. He'll get sick.
不用 我没事的 我只是...
No, I'm all right. I just...
我只是过来跟你商量 让我再在你那儿干活
I just wanted to come by and talk to you about working some more.
干活? 你没看到外面下了那么大的雨吗?
Work? Don't you see what it's doing out there?
看到了 先生
Yes, sir.
嘿 我的酒呢?
Hey, where's my drink at?
你有他能穿的裤子吗? 你腰围多大?
You got any trousers he can wear? What size waist you got?
我有些短裤他应该能穿
Well, I think I have some cool pants he can wear.
我敢肯定有了那条狗 没人敢来找麻烦
I bet nobody come messing around here with that dog out there.
这也是我买那条狗的原因
Well, that's why I got the dog.
狗才不会管那些路过的人呢
Dog won't bother anybody just walking down the road.
路又不是狗的 狗很讲理的
Road ain't Dog's. Dog knows what's Dog's.
你可以继续走 狗也不会怎样的
You could've just walked on off, Dog wouldn't have done anything.
好吧 给你 试试这个
All right. Here, try these on.
我觉得很适合你
I think they'll fit you.
浴室在这边
Bathroom's this way.
它是条好狗
Dog is a good dog.
是啊 但它可吓死我了
Yeah, that dog scared the hell out of me though.
他被打得很惨
He's all beat up.
是他爸爸干的 我亲眼看到了
His daddy. I saw him do it.
什么?
You what?
你就在旁边眼睁睁地看着? 还是怎样?
What, you just sat there and watched it? Or what?
他是大孩子了...
He's a big kid...
我不能插手每件小事
I can't get my hands dirty in every little thing.
你了解我的
You know how I get.
你是大人了 乔
You're a grown man, Joe.
这是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
你想怎么理解都可以
It can mean whatever you want it to mean.
别以为你多了解我
Don't fool yourself too much about me.
嘿 不错嘛
Hey, there you go.
看起来帅极了
You look like a million bucks.
现在觉得好些了吗?
You feel better now?
我觉得衰极了
I feel like a hundred bucks.
我来是想跟你说说工作的事
I come by 'cause I wanted to talk to you about my job.
我想干活 也需要工作
I wanna work and I need a job.
我爸不在乎有没有工作 但我在乎
My daddy don't care if he gots a job, but I do.
这大雨天你也会干活的 对吧?
You'd work in this rain, wouldn't you?
如果需要的话
If you need me to.
等我穿上鞋 然后送你回家
Let me slip my shoes on, and I'll run you back home.
我们马上跟来 好吗?
Hey, we'll be there in just a second, okay?
嘿...
Hey...
你不必受别人气的 知道吧?
You know you don't have to take no shit from nobody, right?
你知道的 对吧?
You know that, right?
是 女士
Yes, ma'am.
很好
Good.
那我们走吧
Now, let's go.
- 近来如何 克里斯?  - 挺好 你呢?
- How you been, Chris?  - Good, how about you?
还行 你还在搞综合格斗吗?
Yeah, all right. You still doing the Mixed Martial Arts?
是的
Yes, sir.
你大雨天出来干嘛 乔?
What are you doing out in the rain, Joe?
我要买两磅火腿和一磅切片蜂窝奶酪
I need two pounds of ham and a pound of Swiss cheese sliced up.
好的 你来拿奶酪 我拿火腿
All right. Come on, you get the cheese, and I'll get the ham.
- 好  - 好像每次赶上点进度 就又开始下雨了
- Yes, sir.  - Looks like every time I get a little ahead, it starts in raining again.
给你
Here you go.
这些没多少 听我说
It's not much. Now, look here.
等天晴了 你天亮前就一早来这儿
When it dries up, you come down here early in the morning before light,
我来接你 然后送你去干活
and I'll pick you up and take you to work.
天好了 我们有很多活要干
We've got plenty to do when the weather gets right.
你有闹钟吗?
You got a clock?
不 你肯定没有
No, you wouldn't. All right.
那我给你找个发条闹钟什么的
I'll find you a wind-up clock or something.
就这样吧
All right, then.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
你不用一直叫我先生
You don't need to call me sir all the time.
我是你朋友 懂了吗?
I'm your friend. You understand?
好的 嘿 火腿呢?
All right. Hey, where's his ham?
- 等下 马上好  - 好吧
- Hang on. We're coming.  - All right.
你想什么呢 乔?
What are you thinking, Joe?
什么也没有
Nothing.
我讨厌无能为力的感觉
There's nothing I can do and I hate it.
不是这样的
That's not true.
就是的
Yeah, it is.
你看着我 好像我应该插手一样
You look at me like I can make a move.
你为什么要那么看着我? 你不在乎吗?
What are you thinking when you look at me like that? Don't you care?
我不知道我是谁
I don't know who I am,
我只知道忍耐让我活到了今天
but I know what keeps me alive is restraint.
让我不进监狱
Keeps me out of jail.
让我不伤害别人
Keeps me from hurting people.
嘿
Hey.
万事都有原因这扯淡的信仰让我变成这样
A mark of some fucked-up faith that there's a reason.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这一切都有原因
A reason for all of this.
所以大多数时候我不能做我想做的
A reason in most moments I shouldn't do what I wanna do.
而做我该做的
I do as I'm told.
快 装好车 赶紧离开这儿
Come on, let's load up. Let's get outta here.
这些人累死累活地工作
These men who bust their asses work like dogs.
我也信任他们 但他们每天都会受伤
And I believe in them, but every day they hurt.
他们一天天变老 被晒脱皮...
They get old, they peel back...
露易丝的 朱尼尔的
Lewis. Junior.
这里没有战场
There's no frontier anymore.
萨米的
Sammy.
阿兰的
Alan.
克拉克的
Clark.
盖瑞的
Gary.
我看着这孩子
And I watch that boy.
就好像看到了...
I see someone who's...
一个跟我完全不像的人 但是...
who's nothing like me, but...
他是个孩子 被人们遗忘了
He's a child, folks left behind.
他冷眼旁观着
And he's on the fence,
不露声色
balanced right there.
你想做什么?
What do you want?
你想要什么?
What is it you want?
没什么
Nothing.
只管告诉我能做什么
Just tell me what I can do.
我喜欢你
I like you.
我也喜欢你 但这有什么意义呢?
I like you, too, but what's the point in any of it?
真他妈操蛋
Fuck to this day.
操他妈的
I mean, fuck to this day.
最终玉石俱焚 物是人非...
It's all just gonna boil up and wash us away...
或许你还会在这儿
Maybe you'll still be here.
或许你不会
Maybe you won't.
该死的 乔 你为什么非让一群人坐这小破卡车呢?
Damn, Joe. Why you keep loading all these fools in this little truck?
有你可真开心啊 萨米
Good to have you with us again, Sammy.
再向下滑一点 我们就得出来推车了
It drop down any lower, we gonna have to get out and push,
我绝不会推的
and I ain't pushing shit.
乔 我以为他们会给你一辆新卡车
Joe, I thought they had y'all on a new truck, Joe.
我没有新卡车
I ain't getting no new truck.
那你需要一辆
You need one.
不需要的
No, I don't.
乔 如果你买辆新车 这个旧的你卖多少钱?
Joe, if you get a new truck, how much you want for this old one?
你说这个破烂吗?
You mean this old piece of junk?
闻起来跟死过人似的 烂死了
Smells like somebody died up in there. It's nasty.
我不介意有味道 我喜欢 我闻着挺好的
I don't mind the smell. I like it. Smells good to me.
但这辆车
Yeah, but this thing,
修它的时间跟开的时间一样长
I spend as much time working on it as I do driving it.
当然了 它没什么大问题
Of course, there ain't nothing major wrong with it.
只是车嘛 需要休息一下
It's just little shit, you know. It needs some brakes.
需要...
It needs...
乔 拜托啦
Joe. Come on.
我向你买 我会很努力工作
I'll buy it from you, I'll work my butt off.
我爱这辆车 你现在就得给我
I love the truck, you have to give it to me now.
这个...
Well, I mean, it's...
它都开了好久了
It's got a lot of miles on it.
你最好在镇上买一辆
You'd be better finding one in town somewhere.
我不想在镇上买 我喜欢这辆
Well, I don't want one in town. I like that one.
拜托嘛 乔
Come on, Joe.
好吧 那我卖九百块
All right, I'll take $900 for it,
前提是买了新车后
if I get a new truck.
好的! 一言为定
All right! Shake hands.
这才爽快嘛 真棒
That's what I'm talking about. Heck, yeah.
嘿
Hey,
你拿的什么?
what you got there?
你好!
Hey!
我想问你能不能告诉我怎么去清水镇
I was wondering if maybe you could tell me how to get down to Water Valley.
我妻子在那里的医院
My wife, she in the hospital down there.
我才来的这儿
I just now got here.
你知道有多远吗?
You know how far it is?
是走那条公路吗?
Is that the highway that goes to it?
是吗?
Is it?
你喝什么呢?
What you drinking?
没什么
Nothing.
没什么?
Nothing?
你不是在喝酒吧?
You ain't drinking some wine, are you?
我...
I...
这没什么不对
Yeah, nothing wrong with that.
有人认为樵夫应该滴酒不沾
Some folks think a feller ought not drink at all,
但小酌对人无害啊
but a little drink never hurt nobody.
没错
That's right.
我在家的时候就时不时喝点
I get me a little drink every now and then when I'm down at the house,
但我老伴儿 对此很小题大做
but the old lady, she raises so much sand about it,
我在这儿不怎么喝了
I don't do a lot of drinking down there.
一般等到去镇上的时候 比如这会儿
I usually wait until I get uptown like I am now.
买杯酒
Grab me a drink.
她还好吗?
She all right?
是的 今天很好
Well, yeah, she is today.
所以我才来这儿 想去清水镇看看她
That's why I'm trying to get down there to Water Valley, to go see about her.
我今天该拿工钱的
I supposed to get paid today,
但那个老家伙 一直没出现
but the old fella, he never showed up.
所以我想着给自己弄点酒
You know, so I think I'll go get me a little drink,
去清水镇看看她怎么样了
go down to Water Valley and go see how she's doing.
她在医院里?
She in the hospital?
对 在医院 她得癌症了
Yeah, she in the hospital. She got cancer.
慢慢被吞噬 直到死去
Just eat up with it, all over.
可怕的东西...
You know, damn thing...
人是一天天活着
You know, a person just don't know from one day to the next
不知道哪天就是最后一日了
which one's gonna be their last.
今天天气不错
Hell, it's a beautiful day out, but
但骨头里觉得有点冷
feeling a little chill in my bones.
应该是要下雨了
I think it's fixing to rain.
看起来肯定会下雨...
Look like it's fixing to rain some...
恩 这才对...
Yeah. Here we go...
三条非洲野犬
Three African painted dogs,
野狗 在动物园杀死了一个三岁孩子
wild dogs, killed a three-year-old in a zoo.
学步的孩子...
A toddler...
掉到笼子里 伤到了头
He fell in, hit his head,
被狗抓住了
the dogs got him.
大人们都干嘛去了?
Where was everybody?
他只是个小孩子
He was a little kid.
你好 乔
Hello, Joe.
怎么样啊?
How you doing?
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
给你说 伙计
I tell you what, buddy.
就这么你来我往 恩恩怨怨
All this goddamn back and forth and back and forth.
老子真是受够了
I'm fucking over it.
天啊
Hell,
或许我们是时候...
maybe it's time we just...
握手言和了
bygones.
你知道我能要你命的 对吧?
You know I could have killed you, right?
我能要你命 但我没有
I could have killed you, but I didn't.
子弹只是擦身而过 因为我是瞄着树的
I licked you, I was aiming for the trees, see.
那枪只是给你个警告
That shot was meant as a warning shot.
因为你一直在我朋友
'Cause all you keep doing is embarrassing me
面前羞辱我
in front of my goddamn friends.
妈的 你上次煽我的时候所有人都在场
I mean, hell, last time you slapped me there was ladies and gentlemen present.
我听说了 给你干活的小孩是怎么回事?
So what's this shit I hear about this kid you got working for you?
一个小流浪儿
Little drifter kid,
大概这么高?
about yay big?
我才不关心他呢
I don't really give a shit about him,
但我猜你知道他住哪 对吧
but I suspect you know where he lives, don't you.
不知道?
No?
你怎么了 怪人?
What's wrong, spooky?
还生我气呢?
Still sore at me?
克里斯蒂 在死人前赶紧报警
Kristy, call the cops before somebody gets killed.
行吗 亲爱的?
Will you do that for me, honey?
等下!
Hold on!
嘿 回去 等下...
Hey, get back, hold on...
- 嘿 乔  - 梅尔在吗?
- Hey, Joe.  - Is Merle around?
梅尔不在 你没事吧?
Merle ain't here. You all right?
我想找人来一发 但是...
I wanna get blown, but...
你不喜欢狗 对吧?
That's right you don't like dogs, do you?
不是 我爱狗 只是不喜欢这只
That's not true. I love dogs, just not that dog.
这条狗太混账
That dog is an asshole.
对不起 乔
I'm sorry, Joe.
你们给我把这死狗弄出去!
Y'all help me get this fucking dog outta here!
乔
Joe.
忙吗?
You busy?
来吧
Come on.
你养宠物吗?
Got any pets?
我是有只猫
I mean, I had a cat.
猫? 不错 叫什么名字?
Cat? Beautiful. What's his name?
叫密西
Missy.
- 你给它喂什么?  - 不知道 一些干粮
- What'd you feed it?  - I don't know, fucking dry food.
你最喜欢的颜色是什么?
What's your favorite color?
红色
Red.
给我来一发
Blow me.
好吧
All right.
让我好好看看雪花
Let me just focus on the snowflake.
墙上的雪花
The snowflake on the wall.
好吧 雪花
Okay, snowflakes.
好 好 好了...
All right. All right. All right...
抱歉
Beg your pardon.
没关系 宝贝
All right, baby.
没什么
It's all right.
你没必要走 你想的话可以留下来
You don't have to run off. I mean, you can stick around if you want.
乔?
Joe?
狗狗
Dog.
停车!
Pull over!
马上停车!
Pull over, now!
我去! 搞什么!
Come on! What the fuck!
别动!
Don't move!
别动 乔!
Freeze, Joe!
快 把枪放下
Come on, put the gun down,
别紧张 有话好好说!
be a man about it, and show me what you got!
我们把你包围了 乔
We got you surrounded, Joe.
嘿 我就一个人
Hey, I'm just one dude.
别动 乔 把手放到脑后!
Freeze, Joe. Put your hands behind your head!
少来! 你要干什么?
Come on! What are you gonna do?
你看 我什么武器都没带
Look. I don't have nothing on me, man.
别动!
Freeze!
你们为什么不成熟一点 把枪放下
Why don't you guys both be like big boys, and put your guns down,
咱们好好说话呢
and let's talk about it.
我只想好好说话 好吗?
That's all I'm gonna do, just talk about it. All right?
- 过来 乔!  - 快点
- Bring it, Joe!  - Come on.
谁来铐我?
Who's gonna cuff me?
你有什么本事? 我今天感觉特别好
What do you got? I'm feeling real good today.
嘿 乔?
Hey Joe?
你在吗 乔?
You're in there, Joe?
我进来了 乔...
Coming in, Joe...
乔在吗?
Joe here?
你见到乔了吗?
You seen Joe?
想什么呢?
What do you think, man?
你觉得乔会来保护你?
You think Joe's gonna take care of you?
你觉得乔是你爸爸?
You think Joe's your daddy?
你是这样想的吗?
Is that what you think?
乔才不是你爸爸
Joe ain't your daddy.
我才是你爸爸
I'm your daddy.
我才是照顾你的那个人
I'm the one taking care of you.
你有钱吗?
You got some money?
我知道你有钱藏在这附近 你的钱在哪里?
I know you got some money hid around here. Where's your money at?
我他妈的没钱 乔今天没给我钱
I ain't got no damn money. Joe didn't give me none today.
真的吗?
Really?
给我点钱
Gimme some money.
我跟你说了 我他妈的没钱
I just told you I ain't got no damn money.
你没钱?
Ain't got no money?
有食物
Got food.
你有食物 该死的!
You got food, God damn it!
你有食物 却他妈的没钱
You got food, but you ain't got no fucking money.
那你的食物是怎么来的?
How'd you get the food?
你还跌跌撞撞在这里干啥? 你他妈的连自己都照顾不好
What the hell you stumbling for? You can't even take care of your damn self.
那他娘的是我的!
Hey, that's my shit!
你他妈找打是吧 找打
Knock your shit off, boy. Knock your shit off.
你这混账说没钱?
You ain't got no motherfucking money, huh?
嘿 看这儿
Oh, hey. Lookie here, huh?
- 什么...  - 哦 对了!
- What seems to be the...  - Oh, yeah!
这就对了!
Yeah, yeah!
对了 对了
Yeah, yeah.
我刚他妈的就是这么想的
That's kinda what I fucking thought.
打呀 混账
Bring it, motherfucker.
他妈的别碰我!
Get the fuck back off me!
这下怎么样?
How's that?
像那样 是吧? 就像那样
Just like that, huh? Just like that.
是啊 怎么?
Yeah. What?
你小子现在咋不吭声了
You don't seem to be doing a whole lot of talking right now.
看起来你身体挺糟糕的嘛
You kinda look like you in bad shape.
你以为你算个啥? 你才不是我爸爸 狗娘养的
Who the hell do you think you are? You ain't my daddy, you motherfucker!
看着我! 你看到我在桥上对那个混蛋做的了吗?
Look at me! You seen what I did to that motherfucker on the bridge?
我要把你打得屁滚尿流!
I'll beat your ass!
狗娘养的 我受够了和你混在一起了
Son of a bitch, I'm about through messing with you.
我一直在外面弄他妈的钱!
I been out looking for fucking money!
我他妈的一直在外找工作
I've been out looking for a fucking job
来养活你这个没用的家伙!
to feed your worthless fucking face!
是啊 你这个愚蠢的混蛋
Yeah, you stupid little piece of shit.
是啊...
Yeah...
我知道你这附近藏着钱
I know you got money hid around here, boy.
你知道吗?
You know what?
我还会再回来
I'm gonna come back.
我会拿到钱的
I'm gonna get it.
我会找到它 然后得到它
I'm gonna find it, and I'm gonna get it.
嘿 醒醒 醒醒
Hey, wake it up. Wake it up.
厄尔 请给我支该死的香烟
Earl, please get me a goddamn cigarette, man.
求你了
Please, I'm begging you.
不管怎样你反正要出去了 伙计
You're on your way out of here anyway, man.
好吧
All right.
- 我帮你把你的保证人叫过来了  - 谢啦 伙计
- I called your bondsman for you.  - Thanks, buddy.
凭什么他就能出去?
How come he getting out of here?
闭嘴 库奇! 别吵了!
Knock it off, Cokie! Knock it off!
伙计 太谢谢你了
Man. Thank you so much, buddy.
太谢谢了
Thank you, buddy.
该死
Fucking hell.
他们要怎么起诉我?
What do they got me charged with?
该死的 多着呢 酒后驾车 袭警 拒捕
Shit, a heap. DUI, assault on an officer, resisting arrest.
你还想要其它什么吗?
You want some more shit?
你知道他们把我的卡车拖到哪儿去了吗? 有个小孩想买我的车
You know where they took my truck? There's a kid that wants my truck.
昨晚不在这儿 不过我们能找到的
Wasn't here last night. But we can sure find out though.
你第一次进监狱的时候是三十二岁
You were 32 when you went to the pen the first time.
你现在几岁了? 四十八? 四十九?
What are you now? 48? 49?
四十八
48.
你越来越老了 乔
Getting old, Joe.
每次出去重拾生活越来越难了
Be a lot harder on you every time from here on out.
不过我也没资格教你怎么生活
But who am I to tell you how to live your life.
- 对 说得好  - 来吧 伙计
- Yeah. That's a good one.  - Come on, man.
来吧 振作起来
Come on, get it together.
该死的 你跟我开玩笑呢吧?
Shit, man. Are you kidding me?
对 我想要个号码... 像救助狗的 或者...
Yeah, I'd like to get a number on a... Like a dog rescue, or...
你没有救助狗的电话号码?
You don't have a number on a dog rescue?
我要上报一条走失的狗
Well, I'm reporting a lost dog.
对 是一只美国牛头犬
Yeah, it's American Bulldog.
棕白相间 母的
Brown and white, female,
九十磅重
90 pounds.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
柯尔曼先生告诉我 你和警察惹了点麻烦
Mr. Coleman told me you got into a little trouble with some cops.
你听到的就那些?
That all you heard?
他还说你被关进监狱里去了
He said you got put up at that jail, too.
你不会还想要我的卡车吧 想要吗?
You don't still want my truck, do you?
想要 先生
Yes, sir.
真的?
You do?
他说你有一次进了个大监狱
He said you got put up at the big jail one time.
柯尔曼告诉你的?
Coleman told you that?
对
Yeah.
对 我去过 我...
Yeah, I have. I...
我因为袭警 在监狱里待了二十九个月
I did 29 months in the penitentiary for assault on a police officer.
他们逼我把车停在市郊的一个购物中心后面
They pulled me over behind a shopping center uptown.
有这么一个警官
This one officer,
长得挺好看的那种
pretty-boy type guy,
跟我有些过节
had some issue with me.
以为我和他认识的一个女孩有点关系
Thought I had something to do with one of the girls he knew.
而我根本就不知道他到底在讲什么
And I didn't know what the hell he was talking about.
然后在我把他们三个都暴打一顿之后
Then they tried to shoot me,
他们想向我开枪
after I beat the shit out of all three of them.
其中一个就这么做了
Or one did.
副警长去拿他的枪 我抢来了
Deputy went for his gun and I grabbed it.
然后...
And...
他铁了心要杀我 他是这么告诉我的
Well, he was fixing to kill me, he told me he was.
他所做的就是把他的膝盖骨给崩了...
All he did was blow his kneecap off...
那个蠢蛋
The jackass.
我的狗昨晚跑掉了
My dog run off last night.
你想去找她吗?
You wanna go look for her?
好啊
Sure.
- 你想让我来开这卡车?  - 反正迟早要开始的
- You want me to drive the truck?  - Gotta start sometime.
别看他们 别向他们挥手
Don't look at them. Don't wave to them.
他们知道你挥手就意味着你犯了什么罪
Because they know you're guilty of something when you wave.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
对 只要警察想 他就能搞死你
Yeah, a cop can mess you up if he wants to.
对 我是犯过错
Yeah, I made the mistakes,
但是他们不肯让我改过自新
but they're the ones that won't ever let me live it down.
嘿 我能从你这儿买瓶啤酒吗?
Hey, can I buy one of them beers off of you?
我不知道
I don't know.
你可以喝一瓶啤酒 但是不能从我这儿买一瓶
You can drink one of these beers, but you cannot buy one from me.
朋友们从不用从我这儿买东西
Friends don't ever need to buy things from me.
拿去吧 又冰又爽
There you go, nice and cold.
睁大你的眼睛
Now, keep your eyes peeled.
看警察还是看狗?
For the cops or the dog?
都要...
Both...
警察还是狗
Cops or the dogs.
你听到了吗?
You hear that?
这种声音能让妓女激动起来
That's the sound that gets the hookers excited.
她们知道你有钱 她们听到这个...
They know you got cash. They hear that...
你想学学怎么做个冷酷的表情吗?
You wanna learn how to make a cool face?
好 解剖一下冷酷的表情
All right. Anatomy of a cool face.
做一个痛苦的表情...
Make a face of pain...
现在笑一个
Now smile.
不是 是在痛苦上接着笑
No, smile on top of the pain.
保留痛苦的表情 痛着笑
Hold the pain. Smile through it.
你没醉吧?
You ain't drunk, are you?
该死 最好我来开车
Shit, I'd better drive.
你知道吗 盖瑞? 你可以做到的
You know what, Gary? You got it made.
想想你将会上的好多美女
Because think about all the beautiful girls you're gonna fuck.
我以前认识一个住在这附近的女孩
I used to know a girl that lived around here.
该死的 我的狗在哪里?
Shit, where's my dog?
我把它从小养大的
I raised that dog from a pup.
- 菲丝!  - 这儿有好多施工场地
- Faith!  - There's lots of construction here,
因为他们在造一个印度寺庙
because they're building a Hindu temple.
会有很多邦巴小孩
Gonna have lots of Bombanese kids.
他们头中心有小红点
Little red dots in the center of their head,
像激光束一样
like a laser beam.
菲丝!
Faith!
你最好多练练冷酷的表情
You better work on that cool face.
你得站得像是你是地主一样 好吗?
You gotta stand like you own land, right?
现在 做个痛苦的表情 好吗?
Now, you make the pain face, right?
你脑子里有好多东西
You got a lot on your mind.
现在笑一个
Now smile.
对了 就像是
Yeah, it's like,
"我脑子里有好多事 但是我能做到 我能完成的"
"I got a lot on my mind, but I can do it. I can get through it."
对 你找到门道了嘛 你做到了
Yeah, there you go, you're getting it.
对了 很酷啊!
Yeah, that's cool!
狗重一百磅
Dog weighs 100 pounds.
耳朵很长 尾巴断了...
Has long ears, with a docked tail...
那是什么?
What was that?
是的 女士 我是想找时间好好做的
Yes, ma'am, I meant to get around to doing that,
但是我还没把我的狗照顾到底
but I did a halfway job on my dog.
没照顾到底?
A halfway job?
- 没到底 女士  - 那么 怎么没到底?
- Halfway, ma'am.  - Well, halfway how?
没到底
Halfway.
你好?
Hello?
- 你好?  - 我能帮你们什么吗?
- Hello?  - Can I help you fellas?
你好 我的狗不见了 它是...
Hello. So I'm missing my dog, and the dog is...
- 你想来一些吗?  - 不用了 那会让我疯狂的
- You want some of this?  - No, that stuff'll make you crazy.
哦 我离疯狂还早着呢
Well now, I'm a pretty long way from crazy.
我的狗大约一百磅 棕白相间
My dog is about 100 pounds, brown and white,
看起来像头奶牛
looks like a cow.
- 看着像头奶牛?  - 对
- Looks like a cow?  - Right.
你有只看起来像奶牛的狗?
You have a dog that look like a cow?
这算不上什么大事 很多狗看起来像奶牛
Well, it's not that big a deal. A lot of dogs look like cows.
事情是这样 如果你恰好看到我的狗
But here's the thing, if you happen to see my dog,
不管什么时候
no matter what time,
打电话给我...
you call...
- 不管白天还是晚上 好吗?  - 好
- Day or night. All right?  - Okay.
我们找过你最后看到狗的地方了吗?
Have we already done passed that place where you last saw your dog?
没啊 怎么?
No, Why?
我觉得狗会在那里
I think the dog'll be there.
不 狗会跑走的
No, the dog run off.
如果我是狗 那就是狗会待的地方
If I was dog, that's where dog would be.
也是我会去的地方
That's where I would go.
- 谢谢 女士  - 你和他在一起要小心 好吗?
- Thank you, ma'am.  - Now, you be careful with him, okay?
没问题
All right.
开车小心
Be careful driving, baby.
打给我
Call me.
好
Okay.
真见鬼
I'll be damned.
别 等等 等等 不要
No, wait. Wait, don't.
这狗喜欢你
Dog likes you.
它身上有好多伤疤啊
It has a lot of scars.
对
Yeah,
但是其它和它打架的狗
but all the others,
全都死了
all the others is dead.
谢谢你帮我找到狗
Thanks for helping me find my dog.
先生 没关系
Yes, sir, no problem.
你工作很勤奋
You work hard.
你心很好
You got a good heart.
有任何人找你麻烦
Anybody messes with you,
跟我说就好
you let me know.
我来打他们一顿
I'll fuck them up.
好
Right.
拿着它...
Take it...
你会需要它的
You gonna need it.
- 不  - 搞定女孩...
- No.  - Get girls...
看到了吗? 拿着吧
See? There you go.
就是这样
That's it.
做得很好嘛
You got it.
谢谢
Thank you.
这算不上什么 拿着吧
It ain't anything. You got it.
我要把这个带去听歌剧
I'll take this one to the opera.
去听歌剧 好啊
To the opera, yeah.
该死的 我没打火机了
Shit, I don't have a lighter.
昨天的数据显示
The numbers from yesterday,
官方说的最高温是九十二度
we had a high of 92, officially,
比平均温度九十度高了两度
that's two degrees above the average of 90 for the day.
最低温度六十八度...
68 was our low...
你有打火机吗?
You got a light?
- 有  - 上车
- Yeah.  - Hop in.
那个男孩是个好工人
That boy's a good worker.
那是我这辈子做过的最努力的工作了
That's the hardest fucking work I ever done in my life.
- 那是吗?  - 是啊
- Is it?  - Yeah.
- 你付我儿子钱吗?  -什么?
- You paying my boy?  - What?
- 你付我儿子钱吗?  - 该死 对!
- Are you paying my boy?  - Hell, yeah!
我没见他拿过钱
I ain't seen he got paid none.
说不定他很聪明 存起来了
Well, he probably saves it 'cause he's smart.
从我这儿买了这辆车
Buying this GMC off of me.
买了啥?
Doing what?
- 没什么  - 好
- Nothing.  - Yeah.
他没那么聪明
He ain't so smart.
他什么都不懂
He don't know nothing.
你也不懂
Hell, neither do you.
我跟你直说吧
I'm gonna shoot you straight.
那孩子干的很辛苦!
That boy works his ass off!
他挣的钱
He's earned money,
是他自己的!
and it's his!
如果这车是垃圾的话
If this truck's a piece of shit,
你就滚下去吧
then you need to get out of it.
如果我发现那孩子又受谁欺负的话
And if I find out something has happened to that boy,
我会给那人点儿颜色看看
I'm gonna whip whoever's ass had something to do with it.
在我把你打得满地找牙之前
Now get the hell away from me,
最好给我滚远点
before I knock what's left of your fucking teeth out.
我今天有个很可笑的想法
I had the funniest thought today.
我想咱俩可以出去吃个晚餐
I thought maybe you and I could go out to dinner.
懂吗?
You know?
穿得正式点
Get all dressed up.
你还可以为我开门
And maybe you could hold the door open for me.
那样多好
I think that would be nice.
虽然你在装睡
You pretend to be asleep,
但我知道 我说错了话你还会哭
but I know you'd cry if I said the wrong thing.
你知道这地方很危险 对吗?
You know this place is condemned, right?
不是每个房子随便把窗户上木板拆下来 就可以住人的
You can't just take boards off windows and call a place home.
盖瑞 你为什么还留在这?
Gary, why do you stick around like this?
你已经够成熟 够聪明了 你可以做自己想做的了
You're old enough, smart enough, to do your own thing.
现在最重要的
What's most important right now is me
是照顾多萝西和妈妈
taking care of Dorothy and Momma,
因为我们现在有点家庭纠纷
'cause we kinda gota family problem right now.
嘿
Hey, there.
嘿...
Hey, now...
她不怎么说话?
Don't talk much, does she?
她根本不说
She don't talk at all.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
不知道 没人知道 某一天她就突然不说了
I don't know. Nobody knows. She just stopped one day.
我是说她原来会说 但...
I mean she used to would, but...
嘿 如果你准备好的话 我们去交易吧
Well, hey, I'm ready to make this deal if you are.
好的
Yeah.
我去拿钱
I'll grab my money.
嘿! 老家伙
Hey! G-Daawg.
别以为我忘了 伙计
Don't you think I forgot about it, bud.
我一直在找你和那孩子
I've been looking for you and that kid.
你那个儿子
That boy of yours,
他肯定以为他明白很多
he sure thinks he knows something.
我认识你 先生
I know you, mister.
你是我朋友吗?
You my friend?
不是
I ain't your friend.
你喜欢做那些鬼脸
Well, you like to make all them funny faces.
我说 你是我朋友吗?
I said, are you my friend?
听着 伙计
Listen, buddy.
我知道怎么让咱俩成为朋友
I think I know a way that you and me can be friends.
在这儿呢
There it is.
看起来很像原来的那辆 长春花蓝 我挺喜欢
It looks just like your old one. Periwinkle blue. I like it.
希望如此
I hope so.
汽油应该足够你开回家了
Now, you got plenty of gas to get home.
如果你想四周转转的话
You might want to stop at Coleman's
去柯尔曼那儿再加点油
and put a little more in it if you plan to ride around.
这个给你
Here.
- 那是什么?  - 买车的钱
- What's that?  - It's money for the truck.
该死 我不担心那个
Hell. I ain't worried about that.
你拿着吧 交保险的时候用得到
You just stick it back in your pocket. You're gonna need it for insurance.
- 交保险干什么?  - 是法律规定的
- What's the insurance?  - Well, yeah, it's a law.
没有保险就不能开车
You can't drive without insurance.
现在还有保险 但我把车签给你之后 你就要自己付钱了
You're covered now, but when I sign it over, you gotta pick up the insurance.
过两天你来我家
I'll tell you what, you come out to the house before long,
我帮你搞定
we'll get you fixed up.
我要走了 你没问题吧?
I'm gonna go on. You gonna be all right?
- 没问题 先生  - 好的
- Yes, sir.  - All right.
你想让我跟着你吗?
You want me to follow you?
不用 没关系的
No, I'll be all right.
嘿 乔
Hey, Joe.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 好车  - 谢啦
- Nice truck.  - Thanks.
还没牌照 你刚入手吗?
You ain't got any tags on it. Did you just get it?
对
Yeah.
你可以对着这个吹一口气吗?
You wanna breathe into this for me?
不 我不想
No, I don't want to breathe into that.
嘿! 嘿! 嘿!
Hey. Hey! Hey!
停下来!
Pull over!
停下!
他妈的! 我什么也没干!
God damn it! I ain't done a goddamn thing!
- 待在车里不要动!  - 我没醉
- Stay in your vehicle!  - I ain't drunk.
你最好找别人瞎闹去 因为我啥也没做!
You better look for someone else to mess with, 'cause I did nothing!
- 把手放到身后  - 你和你的狗屁朋友
- Put your hands behind your back.  - You and your motherfucking friends
再找我麻烦 我要弄死你...
keep messing around with me, I'm gonna hurt you...
把手放到...
Put your hands behind your...
过来!
Come here!
我猜如果我现在开走
I guess if I drive off now,
你就要把猎枪拿出来 开枪打我了?
you're gonna get your shotgun out of the back and shoot me?
- 不会  - 你要开枪吗?
- No.  - You gonna shoot me?
- 不要  - 你可以开
- No.  - You can do it.
真快
That was quick.
你那只疯狗还在吗?
Still got that badass dog?
在呢 在这儿呢
Yeah, around here somewhere.
等一下
Hold on a minute.
别担心 没事
Don't worry, okay.
别担心 别担心
Don't worry. Don't worry.
别担心
Don't worry.
好的
All right.
我听说你有了个孙子
I hear you got a new grandbaby.
- 是吗?  - 是啊 你不知道?
- I do?  - Yeah, you didn't know?
不知道
Not until now.
对 小男孩
Yeah. Little boy.
玛茜在教堂见到他了
Marcy saw him at church.
说他长得跟你希望的一样
Said he looked just like you'd expect him to look.
她说他眼睛长得像你
She said he's got your eyes.
你还好吗?
You Okay?
你儿子都长大了 不是吗?
Your son's all grown now, ain't he?
嗯 长大了
Yeah, all grown up.
他要去干哪行? 执法?
What's he going into? Law enforcement?
我听说是
That's what I heard.
你雇了一个新人干活 是吗?
You got a new man working for you now, don't you?
是的
Yes, I do.
我想你已经见过了
I believe you've met him.
卖力的家伙 有点太热情了
Gung ho fella, a little over-eager.
他在找人约炮呢
He was looking for someone to fuck with.
有可能
Yeah, maybe so.
我要让他去干点活 冷静点
I'll have his ass shuffling papers for a while until he learns to cool down a little bit.
但我担心的不是这个
But that ain't what I'm worried about.
能递给我辣酱吗?
Will you pass the hot sauce?
我来问你个问题 乔 因为我真的很想知道
Let me ask you a question, Joe, 'cause I really want to know.
你为什么想回到过去呢?
Why you wanna go back?
你为什么想回到监禁所呢?
Why you wanna go back to the damn penitentiary, man?
你不能总是去别人家里
Because you can't keep going to folks' houses,
什么也不管 就把别人的狗弄死
killing their dogs, don't matter what else is going on.
你也不能一直跟法律抗争
And you can't keep fist-fighting the law.
法官不会容忍的 他不用容忍
Judge won't put up with it. He don't have to put up with it.
所以他们才建了监狱
That's why they build prisons.
你又让我重新吸烟了 该死
Now you done got me back to smoking, damn it.
我都戒了三个星期了
I been quit for three weeks.
我对你不薄 乔
I haven't mistreated you, Joe.
不是吗? 说实话
Have I? Tell the truth.
是 厄尔
No, Earl.
你在可能的时候都替我说话
You stuck up for me when you could.
我以前情况跟你一样糟
And I used to be as bad as you.
有段时间比我还糟
At one time, you were worse.
对 但我现在很好
Yeah, but I'm cool now.
柯妮 你去哪了 宝贝?
Connie. Where'd you go, baby?
下次记得接电话
Answer the phone next time.
我感觉乔在这里
Yo presiento que Joe está aquí.
乔 是你吗? 你在吗?
Joe, is it you? Estás aquí?
对 是我
Yeah, it's me.
该死
Shit.
出了什么事?
What happened?
我需要借车
I need to borrow the truck.
你怎么了?
What happened to you?
我要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
我要杀了那个老混蛋
I'm gonna kill that old son of a bitch.
别以为我不会 我会做的
You think I won't, but I will.
我要把我的钱拿回来
And I'm gonna get mine back.
我就需要借那车用
I just need to borrow that truck.
进来
Come inside.
过来
Come here.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
我该教你拳击的
I should've given you a boxing lesson.
我不需要 我知道该怎么做
I don't need no goddamn boxing lesson. I know what to do.
我要向他眼睛打一拳
I'll pop him right in the eye.
他打了我 把我扔出了卡车
He whooped my ass and threw me out the truck.
因为他知道我要杀了他
Because he knew that I was gonna kill him.
我能杀他
I could kill his ass.
我能像你那样干脆地杀了他
I could kill him just as good as you could.
我知道你能 我知道你能
I know you could. I know you could.
我知道
I know it.
但你不必这么做
But you don't have to do that.
孩子
Okay, son.
跟我待在这
Just stay here with me.
你会很安全的
You'll be safe here.
我把你妈妈和姐姐带回来
I'll bring your Momma and your sister.
他抓了多萝西
He's got Dorothy.
他带她跑了
He done ran off with her.
他跟一些坏人见了面
He met up with some bad men.
我听见他说了
I heard him talking about it.
脸上有疤的那个男人
That man with the scarred-up face,
我在桥上殴打的那个
the one that I beat down by the bridge.
他一直想报复我
He's been looking for me for what I done did to him.
她没伤害任何人 乔
She didn't hurt nobody, Joe.
应该是我受惩罚的
It should have been me.
你知道她被带到哪里了吗?
Do you know where they took her?
盖瑞
Gary,
告诉我
tell me.
Tell me.
我只需要那车
I just need the truck.
我要去一个地方
To get me some place.
我要大干一场
I'm gonna make trouble.
外面见我
Meet me outside.
三十块
$30.
每个三十块
$30 each.
嗨
Hi.
嗨 你好吗?
Hi, how are you doing?
你还好吗?
You Okay?
不好?
No?
告诉我
Tell me something,
你喜欢鬼脸吗?
you like funny faces?
如果我出事了 你要离开 明白吗?
If anything happens to me, you get your ass outta the way. You hear?
你开着我的车走
You take my truck and get out.
去找柯尔曼
And go get Coleman.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
让他打电话给厄尔
Tell him to call Earl.
该死
Shit.
不 不!
No,no,no!
- 不许动  - 该死
- Don't move.  - God damn it.
要是动的话 我把你们俩都杀了
I'll kill you both if you move.
乔 听我说 这... 这不是看起来那么回事
Joe, listen to me. This... It ain't what it looks like, man.
真的
I'm telling you.
多萝西! 多萝西!
Dorothy! Dorothy!
把她带走 盖瑞
Get her out, Gary.
带着妹妹离开这里
Take your sister and go.
快 快啊!
Go. Go!
我不认识你
You, I don't know you.
- 在我开枪打你之前快跑  - 不 不 不
- Run, before I shoot you.  - No, no, no, no, no.
该死的 乔 听我说 行吗?
God damn it, Joe. Listen to me. Just listen to me, okay?
盖瑞!
Gary!
- 盖瑞!  - 我去叫人帮忙 乔
- Gary!  - I'll get help, Joe.
天啊 那女孩 她不...
God damn it. And that girl, she don't...
他妈的她什么都不懂
She don't know shit about shit, man.
跟她爹一样 她就是一垃圾
She's just a piece of trash just like her daddy.
过不久她就会做这烂事的 我告诉你
And she's gonna be doing this shit in no time, I'm telling you.
真的 伙计
I'm telling you, man.
看着月亮
Look at the moon.
该死的!
God damn it!
去你妈的
Fuck this shit.
如果你想开枪打我 来啊 开枪吧
If you want to shoot me, go ahead and shoot me.
我穿过了挡风玻璃 我他妈的无所谓...
I went through a windshield and I don't give a...
你是我的朋友吗?
Are you my friend?
你都做了什么 乔?
What have you done, Joe?
我们是这样运作的
Here's what we do.
我们晚点开始 从早上八点干到下午四点
We start a little late, around 8:00 in the morning, and we go until 4:00.
我每周五按周结算工钱 有时候我们干的时间长一点
I pay by the week, on Fridays. Some days we go long.
如果每周超过四十个小时 我多付半倍的工资
If we run past 40 hours a week, I pay time and a half.
是件苦差事
It's hard work.
我不喜欢太多人聚集在一起
I don't like a whole lot of standing around.
我们卖力点做 到四月底就可以分散一点
We'll probably bust our ass and get this spread out by the end of April.
把所有幼苗都种上
Get out all the bare root seedlings.
有时候为了保持矮小幼苗的稳定 用木棍支撑一下
Sometimes, we stake them if we got to keep the little ones stable.
大部分时间我们还是让他们自由生长
Most of the time we don't need to mess with them little pine seedlings like that.
我要你去加入在农场西边唐·L的队伍
I'm gonna have you join Don L. and his crew on the west end of the farm.
如果那一片进行顺利的话
Then if everything goes good on that acreage,
到了夏天我会让你帮我监督在马尼亚的项目
I'll have you help me supervise the Manea project next summer.
有时候 老混蛋的钱很不好赚
Old bastards can be hard to work for sometimes.
不过 既然你原来给乔干活
But hell, if you worked for Joe,
我觉得你会干好的
I think you'll do just fine.
你有问题吗?
You got any questions?
没有 先生 我什么时候开始?
No, sir. When can I start?
如果你准备好了 现在就开始吧
Right now, if you're ready.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
你认识乔?
So you knew Joe?
当然
Yeah, sure did.
乔是个好人
Joe's a good man.
反正对我来说是
Good man to me anyways.
对我也是
Good man to me too.